Guide to the Aaron Copland Oral History
Aaron Copland Oral History
Oral History of American Music
Aaron Copland Oral History - TEST
1948 1989
1980 1989
OHVI
Oral History of American Music
117 Computer Files
Perlis, Vivian
General
68 interviews. This finding aid describes digitized copies of the interview recordings in this collection. Oral History of American Music also holds the original recordings, on a variety of legacy audio and video formats.
Scope and Contents
The Aaron Copland Oral History comprises approximately 75 interviews with colleagues, friends, and family of Aaron Copland (note: for interviews with Copland himself, see the Major Figures in American Music collection). Oral History of American Music (OHAM) founder Vivian Perlis first became friends with Copland while working on the Charles Ives Oral History. Copland later wrote the preface for her book, Charles Ives Remembered. As the Ives project finished, Perlis focused on Copland as her new subject. From 1975 to 1976, she conducted many hours of interviews with Copland and those closest to him. Finally, in 1984 and 1989, their efforts culminated in the autobiographies, Copland: 1900 through 1942 and Copland: Since 1943, co-authored by Perlis.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. The finding aid includes links to stream most interviews online via Oral History of American Music's (OHAM) AV access system, Aviary. Yale users can login to Aviary using their Yale University ID, to stream these interviews without restriction. Other users are able to request access to interviews directly through Aviary. For access instructions, and to request transcripts of an interview, see OHAM's website. This finding aid also includes links to Table of Contents for most interviews.
Some interviews may be restricted. Access to these restricted interviews may only be granted to a patron who has first obtained direct permission from the interviewee or their estate.
Some interviews may not have been digitized or are otherwise not available to stream online. However, these interviews may have been transcribed. Please see contact OHAM for more details.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by surname of interviewee.
Composers United States 20th Century; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990
- Baker, Caroll
  - Baker, Caroll, 1987 May 14; OHVI 951 a; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 28 mins; Transcript Page Count: 11 pages
    Interview Location
    By telephone
    Baker, Caroll, 1930-1983
- Bean, Betty
  - Bean, Betty, 1983 August 3; OHVI 943 a; Owens, William; Approximate Running Time: 32 mins; Transcript Page Count: 11 pages
    New York, NY
    Bean, Betty
- Berger, Arthur
  - Berger, Arthur, 1981 November 13; OHVI 932 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 74 mins; Transcript Page Count: 28 pages
    Cambridge, MA
    Berger, Arthur, 1912-2003
- Bernier, Rosamond
  - Bernier, Rosamond, 1983 February 3; OHVI 933 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 74 mins; Transcript Page Count: 32 pages
    Bernier, Rosamond
- Bernstein, Leonard
  - Bernstein, Leonard, 1983 September 22; OHVI 962 a-d; Approximate Running Time: 149 mins
    Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990
- Burkat, Leonard
  - Burkat, Leonard, 1986 March 26; OHVI 952 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 76 mins; Transcript Page Count: 30 pages
    Danbury, CT
    Burkat, Leonard, 1919-1992
- Clurman, Harold
  - Clurman, Harold, 1979 May 20; OHVI 901 a-c; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 105 mins; Transcript Page Count: 50 pages
    Clurman, Harold, 1901-1980
- Conroy, William
  - Conroy, William, 1981 March 26; OHVI 920 a; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 44 mins; Transcript Page Count: 19 pages
    Yale Club, New York, NY
    Conroy, William
- Copland, Irving
  - Copland, Irving, 1981 April 7; OHVI 917 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 74 mins; Transcript Page Count: 38 pages
    Roosevelt Island, NY
    Copland, Irving
- Copland, Milton
  - Copland, Milton, 1981 June 2; OHVI 925 a; Owens, William; Approximate Running Time: 21 mins; Transcript Page Count: 10 pages
    Copland, Milton
- Curtin, Phyllis
  - Curtin, Phyllis, 1986 August 6; OHVI 947 a; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 29 mins; Transcript Page Count: 14 pages
    Curtin, Phyllis
- Daniel, Minna Lederman
  - Daniel, Minna Lederman, 1980 September 17; OHVI 905 a; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 42 mins; Transcript Page Count: 13 pages
    Lederman, Minna, 1896-1995
  - Daniel, Minna Lederman, 1980 October 24; OHVI 905 b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 36 mins; Transcript Page Count: 13 pages
- Davidovsky, Mario
  - Davidovsky, Mario, 1981 September 22; OHVI 929 a-b; Owens, William; Approximate Running Time: 62 mins; Transcript Page Count: 21 pages
    Columbia University, New York, NY
    Davidovsky, Mario, 1934-2019
- De Mille, Agnes
  - De Mille, Agnes, 1980 June 25; OHVI 904 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 46 mins; Transcript Page Count: 20 pages
    De Mille, Agnes, 1905-1993
- Del Tredici, David
  - Del Tredici, David, 1981 December 8; OHVI 938 a; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 28 mins; Transcript Page Count: 13 pages
    New Haven, CT
    Conditions Governing Access
    This material is restricted. Access may be granted to a patron who has obtained direct permission from the interviewee or their estate.
    Del Tredici, David
- Denby, Edwin
  - Denby, Edwin, 1980 December 6; OHVI 910 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 82 mins; Transcript Page Count: 31 pages
    Denby, Edwin
- Diamond, David
  - Diamond, David, 1980 November 10; OHVI 907 a-c; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 112 mins; Transcript Page Count: 49 pages
    Juilliard, New York, NY
    Diamond, David, 1915-2005
- Dreiblatt, Martha
  - Dreiblatt, Martha, 1981 May 20; OHVI 923 a; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 45 mins; Transcript Page Count: 21 pages
    Dreiblatt, Martha
- Druckman, Jacob
  - Druckman, Jacob, 1985; OHVI 965 a; Perlis, Vivian
    Druckman, Jacob, 1928-1996
- Duke, John
  - Duke, John, 1982 December 8; OHVI 944 a; Miratti, Richard; Approximate Running Time: 12 mins; Transcript Page Count: 5 pages
    Northampton, MA
    Duke, John
- Engel, Lehman
  - Engel, Lehman, 1981 June 4; OHVI 928 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 63 mins; Transcript Page Count: 27 pages
    Engel, Lehman, 1910-1982
- Feld, Eliot
  - Feld, Eliot, 1981 January 7; OHVI 913 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 52 mins; Transcript Page Count: 20 pages
    Feld, Eliot
- Fine, Verna
  - Fine, Verna, 1981 November 7; OHVI 931 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 72 mins; Transcript Page Count: 34 pages
    Fine, Verna
  - Fine, Verna, 1987 November 9; OHVI 931 c-e; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 135 mins; Transcript Page Count: 82 pages
- Fizdale, Robert
  - Fizdale, Robert, 1982 February 15; OHVI 936 a-b; Owens, William; Approximate Running Time: 73 mins; Transcript Page Count: 25 pages
    Fizdale, Robert (1920-1995)
- Foss, Lukas
  - Foss, Lukas, 1986 November 4; OHVI 948 a; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 41 mins; Transcript Page Count: 19 pages
    Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009
- Franchetti, Arnold
  - Franchetti, Arnold, 1981 June 25; OHVI 927 a; Owens, William; Approximate Running Time: 40 mins; Transcript Page Count: 16 pages
    Lyme, CT
    Franchetti, Arnold, 1906-1993
- Friedman, Madeleine
  - Friedman, Madeleine, 1981 May 4; OHVI 922 a; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 35 mins; Transcript Page Count: 20 pages
    Friedman, Madeleine
- Furman, Selma
  - Furman, Selma, 1979 December 13; OHVI 909 a; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 43 mins; Transcript Page Count: 15 pages
    Furman, Selma
- Garfein, Jack
  - Garfein, Jack, 1987 May 7; OHVI 953 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 71 mins; Transcript Page Count: 36 pages
    Garfein, Jack
- Ginastera, Alberto
  - Ginastera, Alberto, 1981 November 23; OHVI 946 a-b; Owens, William; Approximate Running Time: 70 mins; Transcript Page Count: 15 pages
    Ginastera, Alberto, 1916-1983
- Goldstein, Sylvia
  - Goldstein, Sylvia, 1989 January 5; OHVI 960 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Transcript Page Count: 44 pages
    Goldstein, Sylvia
- Gould, Morton
  - Gould, Morton, 1982 April 23; OHVI 935 a-b; Owens, William; Approximate Running Time: 71 mins
    Great Neck, NY
    Gould, Morton, 1913-1996
- Haieff, Alexei
  - Haieff, Alexei, 1981 February 26; OHVI 916 a-c; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 81 mins; Transcript Page Count: 32 pages
    Haieff, Alexei, 1914-1994
- Hawkins, Erick
  - Hawkins, Erick, 1985 November 26; OHVI 940 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 86 mins; Transcript Page Count: 39 pages
    Hawkins, Erick
- Heinsheimer, Hans
  - Heinsheimer, Hans, 1981 March 26; OHVI 921 a; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 33 mins; Transcript Page Count: 13 pages
    Heinsheimer, Hans W., 1900-1993
- Johns, Erik
  - Johns, Erik, 1981 November 3; OHVI 937 a-b; Owens, William; Approximate Running Time: 52 mins; Transcript Page Count: 14 pages
    Carmel, NY
    Johns, Erik
- Kober, John
  - Kober, John, 1981 April 22; OHVI 919 a; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 23 mins; Transcript Page Count: 11 pages
    Garden City
    Kober, John
- Kraut, Harry
  - Kraut, Harry, 1987 July 21; OHVI 954 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 96 mins; Transcript Page Count: 40 pages
    Kraut, Harry J.
- Lang, Pearl
  - Lang, Pearl, 1985 December 19; OHVI 945 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 55 mins; Transcript Page Count: 26 pages
    Lang, Pearl, 1921-2009
- Lescaze, Mary
  - Lescaze, Mary, 1980 April 25; OHVI 903 a; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 44 mins; Transcript Page Count: 21 pages
    Lescaze, Mary Hughes, 1901-1983
- Lewis, Bobby
  - Lewis, Bobby, 1981 May 12; OHVI 924 a; Owens, William; Approximate Running Time: 35 mins; Transcript Page Count: 14 pages
    Lewis, Bobby, 1909-1997
- Manziarly, Marcelle de
  - Manziarly, Marcelle de, 1979 May 29; OHVI 964 a
    Manziarly, Marcelle de, 1899-1989
- Marlin, Felice
  - Marlin, Felice, 1981 April 22; OHVI 918 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 44 mins
    Marlin, Felice
- Mittenthal, Arnold
  - Mittenthal, Arnold, 1981 January 15; OHVI 915 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 60 mins; Transcript Page Count: 23 pages
    Mittenthal, Arnold
- Moor, Paul
  - Moor, Paul, 1982 June 1; OHVI 939 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 97 mins; Transcript Page Count: 26 pages
    Peekskill, NY
    Moor, Paul
  - Moor, Paul, 1982 January 7; OHVI 939 c-d; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 86 mins; Transcript Page Count: 15 pages
- Moross, Jerome
  - Moross, Jerome, 1982 March 29; OHVI 926 a; Owens, William; Approximate Running Time: 33 mins; Transcript Page Count: 11 pages
    Moross, Jerome, 1913-1983
- O'Donnell, May
  - O'Donnell, May, 1986 January 23; OHVI 950 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 94 mins; Transcript Page Count: 54 pages
    O'Donnell, May, 1906-2004
- Orbon, Julian
  - Orbon, Julian, 1981 July 9; OHVI 930 a; Owens, William; Approximate Running Time: 47 mins; Transcript Page Count: 20 pages
    Orbón, Julián, 1925-1991
- Palmer, Robert
  - Palmer, Robert, 1983 May 12; OHVI 941 a; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 32 mins; Transcript Page Count: 16 pages
    Palmer, Robert, 1915-2010
- Perry, Tod
  - Perry, Tod, 1987 July 31; OHVI 955 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 93 mins; Transcript Page Count: 44 pages
    West Stockbridge, MA
    Perry, Tod
- Pope, Stuart
  - Pope, Stuart, 1988 July 7; OHVI 958 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 92 mins; Transcript Page Count: 45 pages
    Pope, Stuart, 1921-2005
- Ramey, Phillip
  - Ramey, Phillip, 1987 November 10; OHVI 956 a-d; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 115 mins; Transcript Page Count: 64 pages
    Ramey, Phillip, 1939-
- Robbins, Jerome
  - Robbins, Jerome, 1980 June 19; OHVI 912 a; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 30 mins; Transcript Page Count: 13 pages
    Robbins, Jerome, 1918-1998
- Rorem, Ned
  - Rorem, Ned, 1987 January 21; OHVI 949 a-c; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 76 mins; Transcript Page Count: 35 pages
    Rorem, Ned, 1923-
- Schuman, William
  - Schuman, William, 1983 June 2; OHVI 942 a; Perlis, Vivian; Transcript Page Count: 23 pages
    Schuman, William, 1910-1992
- Shanet, Howard
  - Shanet, Howard, 1987 November 17; OHVI 957 a-d; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 129 mins; Transcript Page Count: 51 pages
    Shanet, Howard
- Shapero, Harold
  - Shapero, Harold, 1980 October 4; OHVI 908 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 73 mins; Transcript Page Count: 33 pages
    Natick, MA
    Shapero, Harold, 1920-2013
- Siegmeister, Elie
  - Siegmeister, Elie, 1982 January 26; OHVI 934 a-b; Owens, William; Approximate Running Time: 62 mins; Transcript Page Count: 26 pages
    Siegmeister, Elie, 1909-1991
- Smit, Leo
  - Smit, Leo, 1981 January 29; OHVI 914 a-c; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 119 mins; Transcript Page Count: 51 pages
    Smit, Leo, 1921-1999
- Sykes, Gerald
  - Sykes, Gerald, 1980 October 24; OHVI 906 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 78 mins; Transcript Page Count: 30 pages
    Sykes, Gerald, 1903-
- Thomson, Virgil
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1979 June 6; OHVI 902 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 56 mins; Transcript Page Count: 20 pages
    Chelsea Hotel, New York, NY
    Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989
- Uris, Harold
  - Uris, Harold, 1980 November 25; OHVI 911 a; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 28 mins; Transcript Page Count: 14 pages
    Uris, Harold D., 1905-1982
- Walker, David
  - Walker, David, 1988 September 27; OHVI 959 a; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 6 mins; Transcript Page Count: 3 pages
    Weston, CT
    Walker, David
- Warfield, William
  - Warfield, William, 1989 February 8; OHVI 961 a; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 25 mins; Transcript Page Count: 12 pages
    Warfield, William
  - Warfield, William, 2002 April 27; OHVI 961 b; Pfeiffenberger, Matthew
    Boston, MA